Anjani Kumar Thakur

Software Engineer

Delhi/NCR | 7011221755 | sunnyfixer3941@gmail.com

Summary

Software Engineer with extensive experience in solving many real-world problems across different domains with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology focused on Computer Science from Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University.

Professional Experience

Software Engineer - R&D

Oct 2018 - Present

CashKaro.com - Gurgaon, Haryana

- **Containerizing and Autoscaling:** Dockerized APIs and Deployed on cloud infrastructure, which helped to autoscale the services during sale periods.
- Sync and Async API Calls: Modified the way of using third party API calls using NodeJS Async which helped to increase productivity up to 40%.
- **Deals Pages:** Created autogenerated pages using the live deals data from different telegram channels.
- Bulk Links AutoPoster/Scheduler: Developed a program that could convert normal links into affiliate links in bulk and multipost on Telegram channels / WhatsApp groups automatically scheduled, broadcasted, etc. This raised a GMV of 2.5 Million rupees and over 8 Million clicks in just 4 days.
- **Earnkaro**:- Developed the progressive web application for affiliate marketing program *earnkaro.com* using PHP, MySQL, iQuery, Bootstrap, Service workers.
- **Student Cashback**:- Developed user historical stats Dashboards which helped the CRM team to make decisions for any particular user for the student affiliate program. Implemented admin CRUD operations on a single page using AJAX calls.
- **API Integration & Calls**:- Using Python Requests library, created scripts to call various network APIs to make the validation process smoother and faster.
- **Centralized Sharing System**:- Developed a Centralized Sharing System for the internal sharing of resources among teams. This allowed teams to share files within the office through a secured server.

Software Development Intern

June 2018 - Oct 2018

Novolnvent Softwares - Noida

Prepared Full Stack websites for prospective clients for the Development team and get through the effective tracking of Analytics on the dashboard. Coordinated with the local and international team and prepared interactive healthcare reports using JavaScript.

- **MHBE-Chatbot**:- Integrated Amazon Lex APIs to train a Chatbot which would respond to the queries for Maryland Health Benefit Exchange's website.
- **UNHIN**:- Developed the Universal Health Information Network's website and used the JS DataMaps parsing JSON data moving the whole website on WordPress writing core PHP scripts and modifying WordPress plugins.

Web Developer

Jan 2016 - May 2018

Freelance

Worked as a freelance web developer for small organizations, who needed to develop their websites for online presence and businesses.

Education

Bachelor of Technology 2015-2019 **Computer Science & Engineering**

Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam Technical University, Lucknow R.D. Engineering College, Ghaziabad Percentage: 81

Intermediate 2012-2014

HSEB Board, Nepal Lord Buddha Higher Secondary School Percentage: 81.2

Secondary 2002-2012

SLC Board, Nepal Vinayak Boarding Secondary School Percentage: 76

Skills

Languages: C, C++, Java, Python, JS, PHP

Tools/ Frameworks: Bootstrap
Polymer JS, Particle JS, MySQL, GIT
Cloud Infrastructure: AWS, GCP
Familiar Areas: Assembly, Java,
Blockchain, Machine Learning and AI,
Agile Software Development with
Testing in different phases of SDLC,
Distributed Systems.

Projects

- STOMETA: Smart Agro System from harvesting to Supply/Chain
- xTTChain : Application for toll tax collection using OCR.
- URL link Shortner
- CRM Dashboards
- 15 + freelance websites

Awards / Achievements

- DR. KALAM STARTUP 1st Position
- GDG- HACKATHON, JIIT-NOIDA 2nd Position | NOV 2017
- HACKDTU, DELHI TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY -3rd Position | OCT 2017